Hurry up and get out. The police will be here soon.
‫أسرع في الخروج من هنا.‬ ‫ستصل الشرطة بعد قليل.‬
But…
‫لكن…‬
Go to Dresden. Wait in the train station square.
‫اذهب إلى "دريسدن". ميدان محطة القطار.‬
Give me the message.
‫أعطني الرسالة.‬
This is it.
‫هذه هي.‬
"Cedok Bridge.The Three Frogs"?
‫"جسر (تشيدوك). الضفادع الثلاثة"؟‬
My father also told me this.
‫وأخبرني والدي بالتالي أيضًا.‬
"If the monster you are chasing has a twin…"
‫"إن كان للوحش الذي تطارده توأم…"‬
The twins' mother is alive and living in Prague.
‫فوالدة التوأم حيّة وتعيش في "براغ".‬
There!
‫هاك!‬
Hey! Give it back!
‫مهلًا! أعيدوه!‬
-Stop it! -Pass it here!
‫- توقفوا!‬ ‫- مرره إلى هنا!‬
It's over there now!
‫أصبح هناك الآن!‬
Cut it out! Give it back!
‫كفى! أعده!‬
Any luck, Mr. Grimmer?
‫هل حالفك الحظ يا سيد "غريمر"؟‬
Did you find the documents you were looking for?
‫هل وجدت المستندات التي كنت تبحث عنها؟‬
Since East and West Germany reunified,
‫منذ أن توحّدت "ألمانيا الشرقية" و"الغربية"،‬ ‫تغيّر الأسلوب المتبع في إدارة هذه الجامعة.‬
Those are all the documents that remain from before.
‫هذه هي المستندات التي تبقت من ذي قبل.‬
I'm sorry to put you in all this trouble, Director Galbreckt.
‫أعتذر عمّا تسببت لك به من متاعب‬ ‫يا حضرة المدير "غالبريشت".‬
It's actually pretty rare to find this much remaining.
‫من النادر حقًا أن يُعثر‬ ‫على هذا الكم من المستندات المتبقية.‬
Since the fall of the Berlin Wall,
‫منذ سقوط جدار "برلين"،‬
nearly all records of East Germany's unethical practices disappeared.
‫وكافة المستندات تقريبًا التي تثبت الممارسات‬ ‫غير الأخلاقية لـ"ألمانيا الشرقية" قد اختفت‬
However, it's quite clear that there was child abuse
‫ولكن من الواضح أن ثمة اعتداءات‬ ‫مورست على الأطفال‬
at the orphanages in former East Germany.
‫في دور الأيتام في "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا.‬
But it's hard to find documents that prove that kind of thing.
‫لكن من الصعب إيجاد مستندات‬ ‫تثبت هذا النوع من الاعتداءات.‬
I bet it is.
‫هذا مؤكد.‬
Orphanages in East Germany were
‫دور الأيتام في "ألمانيا الشرقية"‬
administered by the Ministry of Health and Welfare.
‫كانت تديرها‬ ‫وزارة الصحة والرعاية الاجتماعية.‬
The biggest issue is with children of parents designated as criminals,
‫تتمثل المشكلة الأكبر‬ ‫في أبناء من اعتُبروا مجرمين‬
anarchists, spies, illegal immigrants, or failed defectors.
‫وفوضويين وجواسيس ومهاجرين غير شرعيين‬ ‫أو منشقين فشلوا في الانشقاق.‬
One of the institutions that took care of these children
‫إحدى المؤسسات التي اعتنت بهؤلاء الأطفال‬
was Kinderheim, which was run by the notorious Ministry of Internal Affairs.
‫كانت "كيندرهايم" التي أدارتها‬ ‫وزارة الداخلية سيئة السمعة.‬
It's unclear just how much abuse and inhumane brainwashing
‫لا يتبين مدى ما مُورس من اعتداءات‬ ‫وغسل همجي للأدمغة‬
took place in this one special orphanage.
‫في هذا الميتم المميز عن غيره.‬
That is what I am trying to find out in as much detail as possible.
‫هذا ما أحاول معرفته‬ ‫بأكبر قدر ممكن من التفاصيل.‬
I want to know what happened there.
‫أريد أن أعرف ما حدث هناك.‬
I'll leave no stone unturned.
‫سأبحث عمّا حدث باستفاضة.‬
No stone unturned, eh?
‫باستفاضة؟‬
I see. That sounds like quite a task.
‫مفهوم. أجدها مهمة عصيبة.‬
Everyone who worked there must either be in exile or isn't talking, right?
‫لا بد أن كلّ من عملوا هناك‬ ‫قد نُفوا أو يمتنعون عن التحدث.‬
That's right.
‫هذا صحيح.‬
Even Mr. Schnurr, an instructor here.
‫حتى السيد "شنور"، من كان مدرّسًا هناك.‬
Mr. Schnurr?
‫سيد "شنور"؟‬
He was a teacher at 62 Kinderheim in former East Germany.
‫كان مدرّسًا في "كيندرهايم 62"‬ ‫في "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا.‬
I asked to speak with him, but he turned me down.
‫طلبت التحدّث إليه ولكنه رفض.‬
You should keep an eye on him.
‫يتوجب عليك مراقبته.‬
There's a possibility that Mr. Schnurr abused children
‫ثمة احتمال لأن يكون السيد "شنور"‬ ‫قد أساء معاملة الأطفال‬
when he worked in East Germany.
‫عندما كان يعمل في "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬
Would it be all right if I made copies of these documents?
‫هل يُسمح لي أن أصوّر هذه المستندات؟‬
Of course, go ahead.
‫يُسمح لك بالتأكيد.‬
Mr. Grimmer,
‫سيد "غريمر"،‬
you're a journalist from the former West Germany, right?
‫أنت صحفي من "ألمانيا الغربية" سابقًا، صحيح؟‬
Yes, I was a journalist for a newspaper in Leipzig here in the east.
‫نعم، كنت صحفيًا في صحيفة‬ ‫في "لايبزيغ" هنا في الشرق.‬
Really? I'm surprised that a human rights activist like you was in the east.
‫حقًا؟ من المدهش أن ناشطًا‬ ‫في مجال حقوق الإنسان مثلك كان في الشرق.‬
Yes, well…
‫أجل، في الواقع…‬
At that time, I went all around the world as a foreign correspondent.
‫كنت أجوب الأرجاء آنذاك‬ ‫بصفتي مراسلًا أجنبيًا.‬
They were all missions for the government.
‫كانت كلها بعثات للحكومة.‬
-Understand what I mean? -Huh?
‫- هل تفهم ما أعنيه؟‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
I was a spy.
‫كنت جاسوسًا.‬
Here we go.
‫هيا بنا.‬
That's quite a bag you have there.
‫حقيبتك رائعة.‬
It's packed with documents I've picked up from all over former East Germany.
‫إنها مليئة بمستندات حصلت عليها‬ ‫من جميع أنحاء "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا.‬
I can't wait to read what you put together.
‫أتحرق شوقًا لقراءة ما جمعته.‬
So where are you headed next?
‫إلى أين ستذهب الآن؟‬
Prague in the Czech Republic.
‫إلى "براغ" في جمهورية "التشيك".‬
I appreciate your cooperation, Director Galbreckt.
‫أقدّر تعاونك يا حضرة المدير "غالبريشت".‬
Those other kids sure were pretty mean to you.
‫لا بد أن أولئك الصبية عاملوك بلؤم.‬
I guess they ended up taking your shoes, huh?
‫أرى أنهم أخذوا منك حذاءك.‬
Now, now. Stop crying.
‫هيا، كفاك بكاءً.‬
We humans can do just fine without shoes.
‫بوسع البشر أن يعيشوا من غير أحذية.‬
We were born barefoot, after all.
‫نحن وُلدنا حفاة.‬
But I must say,
‫لكن من الضروري الإقرار،‬
anyone who would bully others and take their shoes is scum.
‫بأن من يتنمر على الآخرين‬ ‫ويأخذ أحذيتهم شخص حقير.‬
There's no reason to let scum like them make you cry.
‫ما من داع يدفعك للسماح بحقير مثله‬ ‫بأن يبكيك.‬
Goodbye.
‫مع السلامة.‬
I guess they're too big to even walk in, huh?
‫أرى أنه أكبر من أن تتمكن من السير به.‬
DRESDEN STATION
‫"محطة (دريسدن)"‬
-Sir, excuse me. -Yes?
‫- أرجو المعذرة يا سيدي.‬ ‫- نعم؟‬
May I bother you for a moment?
‫هل لي بلحظة من وقتك؟‬
Sure. What is it?
‫تفضل. ما الأمر؟‬
Well, actually, I've run into a little problem.
‫أنا في الواقع واجهتني مشكلة.‬
The bag with my passport in it was stolen.
‫الحقيبة التي كان فيها جواز سفري سُرقت.‬
Your passport? Oh dear, that's awful.
‫جواز سفرك؟ ويلاه، كم هذا فظيع.‬
Yes, it's terrible.
‫أجل، إنه لأمر فظيع.‬
I was on my way to see my sister in Vienna.
‫كنت في طريقي لزيارة أختي في "فيينا".‬
My other sister called yesterday to tell me she had collapsed.
‫اتصلت أختي الأخرى في الأمس‬ ‫لتخبرني بأن صحتها تدهورت.‬
She did? Then you'd better go and see her.
‫حقًا؟ يُستحسن بك أن تزورها إذًا.‬
You should report it to the police.
‫يجب أن تبلغ الشرطة.‬
It's okay. I already have.
‫لا داعي لذلك. سبق أن أبلغتهم.‬
The problem is my sister doesn't have the money to pay the doctor.
‫تكمن المشكلة في أن أختي ليس معها مالًا‬ ‫لتدفع أجرة الطبيب.‬
Oh, that's a shame.
‫كم هذا مؤسف.‬
My wallet was also in the bag that was stolen.
‫كانت محفظتي في الحقيبة التي سُرقت.‬
I can't go now,
‫لا يسعني الذهاب الآن،‬
but if I could at least send some money, it would help my sister.
‫لكن إن استطعت على الأقل‬ ‫أن أرسل مبلغًا من المال، فسيساعد أختي.‬
But I can't even do that.
‫لكنني أعجز عن ذلك حتى.‬
How much do you need?
‫كم تحتاج؟‬
Oh, you don't need to do that. I don't need that much.
‫لست مضطرًا إلى ذلك.‬ ‫لست بحاجة إلى مبلغ كبير.‬
All I need is enough to pay for her to be taken to the hospital and see a doctor.
‫كل ما أحتاج إليه هو ما يكفي لدفع‬ ‫تكاليف نقلها إلى المستشفى وعرضها على طبيب.‬
This is all I can manage.
‫هذا كل ما يمكنني دفعه.‬
Thank you. Thank you so much!
‫شكرًا. شكرًا جزيلًا!‬
I swear I'll pay you back.
‫أقسم إنني سأرد لك المال.‬
Write down your address on this.
‫اكتب عنوانك هنا.‬
No, it's all right.
‫لا داعي لذلك.‬
I'm just glad if can help your sister get care.
‫يسعدني أن تساعد أختك‬ ‫على تلقي ما يلزمها من رعاية.‬
Thank you. You're a lifesaver!
‫أشكرك. أنت خير معين!‬
I hope she gets well soon.
‫أتمنى لها الشفاء العاجل.‬
Man, what did you give him money for?
‫عجبًا، لماذا أعطيته المال؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
That guy's clearly lying.
‫من الواضح أن ذلك الرجل يكذب.‬
He is?
‫حقًا؟‬
People like him are always hanging out at the station looking for easy targets.
‫يتسكع أمثاله في المحطة دائمًا‬ ‫بحثًا عن أناس يسهل استغلالهم.‬
How could you let yourself get duped?
‫كيف سمحت له بخداعك؟‬
I got duped?
‫خُدعت؟‬
The express to Prague leaves platform seven at 3:15 p.m.
‫سيغادر قطار رصيف رقم سبعة‬ ‫المتجه إلى "براغ" في الثالثة والربع عصرًا.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
-Thanks, I appreciate it. -Don't mention it.
‫- أشكرك، أنا ممتن لك.‬ ‫- العفو.‬
Thanks for earlier.
‫أشكرك على ما فعلته سابقًا.‬
May I sit here?
‫أيمكنني الجلوس هنا؟‬
Sure.
‫بالتأكيد.‬
Where are you headed?
‫ما وجهتك؟‬
To Prague.
‫"براغ".‬
-You're Japanese, aren't you? -What?
‫- أنت ياباني، أليس كذلك؟‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
Konnichiwa.
‫"كونيتشوا".‬
Domo.
‫"دومو".‬
I've been to Japan.
‫ذهبت إلى "اليابان".‬
How many years ago was that? I remember now, it was 1982.
‫كم سنة مضت؟‬ ‫أتذكر الآن، كان ذلك في عام 1982.‬
Yes. I went to Akihabara.
‫أجل. ذهبت إلى "أكيهابارا".‬
I bought a bunch of listening devices and high-tech equipment there.
‫اشتريت مجموعة من أجهزة التنصت‬ ‫وأجهزة متطورة من هناك.‬
There was a very popular song then too.
‫ثمة أغنية مشهورة جدًا كانت منتشرة آنذاك.‬
Let's see. How does it go?
‫سأحاول تذكّرها. ما كان مطلعها؟‬
Kita no hakabadori na ha
‫"كيتا نو هاكبادوري نا ها"‬
Wait, that's not it.
‫مهلًا، ليست هذه.‬
Kita no…
‫"كيتا نو…"‬
Sakabadori ni ha.
‫"ساكبادوري ني ها".‬
That's right. That's how it goes.
‫صحيح. هذه هي.‬
Kita no sakabadori ni ha
‫"كيتا نو ساكبادوري ني ها"‬
I also bought a plastic model of a robot for my kid. He loved it.
‫اشتريت أيضًا‬ ‫رجلًا آليًا بلاستيكيًا لابني. أعجبه.‬
Where's your son now?
‫أين هو ابنك الآن؟‬
Oh, he's dead now.
‫لقد مات.‬
Immigration control. I need to check your passports.
‫أنا من إدارة مراقبة الهجرة.‬ ‫يجب أن أتحقق من جوازيّ سفركما.‬
Sure.
‫تفضل.‬
Thank you.
‫شكرًا.‬
The river Elbe.
‫نهر "إلبه".‬
I wonder what the trout are like this year.
‫أتساءل عمّا عليه‬ ‫أسماك السلمون المرقط من حال.‬
Not very good.
‫ليست جيدة.‬
Is that right?
‫حقًا؟‬
Last year I caught one this big.
‫اصطدت في العام الماضي سمكة بهذا الحجم.‬
Not this year, you won't.
‫لن يحالفك الحظ هذا العام.‬
Thank you.
‫شكرًا.‬
He knows your passport is a fake.
‫إنه يعرف أن جواز سفرك مزوّر.‬
You better get out of here, Dr. Tenma.
‫يُستحسن بك أن تخرج من هنا يا دكتور "تينما".‬
How do you know who I am?
‫كيف تعرفني؟‬
Never mind that. Now that immigration control realizes
‫لا تشغل بالك بذلك.‬ ‫بعدما أدركت إدارة مراقبة الهجرة‬
your passport is a fake, they'll come after you.
‫أن جواز سفرك مزوّر، فسيأتون للقبض عليك.‬
You better get out of here now, Dr. Tenma.
‫يُستحسن بك أن تخرج من هنا يا د. "تينما".‬
Darn it.
‫اللعنة.‬
Hey, you.
‫يا هذا.‬
We need to get past.
‫نريد أن نمرّ.‬
Oh, I'm sorry.
‫أنا آسف.‬
My bag's so big, it's gotten stuck.
‫حقيبتي كبيرة جدًا، إنها عالقة.‬
It just won't budge.
‫إنها لا تتزحزح.‬
What's your darn problem?
‫ما هي مشكلتك؟‬
Hey, don't jostle it around too much.
‫لا تدفعوها بشدة.‬
What the heck's inside?
‫ما الذي بداخلها؟‬
Some very precious items.
‫أغراض قيّمة للغاية.‬
Ouch! At last, it's free.
‫تحرّرت أخيرًا.‬
Where's the man who was here?
‫أين الرجل الذي كان هنا؟‬
Who?
‫من؟‬
Do you remember the Asian man who was here earlier?
‫أتذكر الرجل الآسيوي الذي كان هنا سابقًا؟‬
Well, maybe he went to the dining car.
‫ربما ذهب إلى عربة الطعام.‬
-You go check the next car. -Yes, sir!
‫- اذهب لتفقد العربة التالية.‬ ‫- حاضر يا سيدي!‬
This is passenger car two. There's an emergency!
‫أتحدث إليك من عربة القطار الثانية.‬ ‫ثمة حالة طارئة!‬
An Asian passenger is carrying a fake passport!
‫ثمة راكب آسيوي معه جواز سفر مزوّر!‬
-What's wrong? -What is it?
‫- ما الخطب؟‬ ‫- ما الأمر؟‬
Stop the train immediately!
‫أوقفوا القطار في الحال!‬
Well done. Very well done.
‫أحسنت صنعًا. أحسنت.‬
They haven't come this way looking for you.
‫لم يأتوا إلى هنا بحثًا عنك.‬
Since the train stopped, I got off.
‫ولأن القطار أُوقف، نزلت.‬
I haven't introduced myself. I'm Grimmer.
‫أنا لم أعرّف عن نفسي. أنا "غريمر".‬
How about I guide you to the border, Dr. Tenma?
‫ما رأيك في أن أرشدك إلى الحدود‬ ‫يا د. "تينما"؟‬
I know this area well. I often come here to fish.
‫أعرف هذه المنطقة جيدًا.‬ ‫غالبًا ما آتي إلى هنا لصيد السمك.‬
Hiking through the mountains won't be easy,
‫التنزه في الجبال ليس سهلًا،‬
but the views will be worth it.
‫لكن المناظر الطبيعية هنا تستحق العناء.‬
How come you're helping me?
‫لم تساعدني؟‬
Well, you see,
‫في الواقع،‬
I worked for a newspaper when Germany was still split.
‫كنت صحفيًا عندما كانت "ألمانيا"‬ ‫لا تزال منقسمة.‬
I'm a freelance journalist now though.
‫لكنني صحفي مستقل الآن.‬
I've read all the articles about you.
‫قرأت كل المقالات التي لها علاقة بك.‬
I'm quite interested in your story.
‫أثارت قصتك اهتمامي بشدة.‬
In East Germany, being falsely accused of crimes was a daily occurrence.
‫كان تُلفّق التهم في "ألمانيا الشرقية"‬ ‫على نحو يومي.‬
Political prisoners were framed with false murder charges.
‫لُفّقت جرائم قتل لسجناء سياسيين.‬
After seeing all that,
‫بعدما شهدت كل هذا،‬
it became pretty easy to tell real criminals from the falsely accused.
‫بت قادرًا بسهولة على التمييز‬ ‫ما بين المجرمين فعلًا والمتهمين زورًا.‬
You're innocent. Isn't that right, Dr. Tenma?
‫أنت بريء. أليس كذلك يا د. "تينما"؟‬
Please stop calling me "doctor."
‫كفّ عن مناداتي بـ"دكتور" رجاءً.‬
What? But you're a talented neurosurgeon, aren't you, Dr. Tenma?
‫ماذا؟ لكنك جرّاح مخ وأعصاب موهوب،‬ ‫أليس كذلك يا دكتور "تينما"؟‬
I'm not a doctor anymore!
‫لم أعد طبيبًا!‬
How do you like it? A darn good view, don't you think?
‫ما رأيك بهذا المنظر؟‬ ‫إنه منظر رائع، ألا تظن ذلك؟‬
From here, we can see if anyone's coming after us too.
‫يمكننا أن نرى من هنا‬ ‫ما إن كان أحدهم يلاحقنا أيضًا.‬
All right then,
‫حسنًا إذًا،‬
why don't we take a little break here?
‫لم لا نأخذ استراحة قصيرة هنا؟‬
How about a sandwich?
‫ما رأيك في تناول شطيرة؟‬
I brought wine as well.
‫أحضرت نبيذًا أيضًا.‬
And some delicious cheese.
‫والقليل من الجبن اللذيذ.‬
I don't have time for this.
‫ما من وقت لهذا.‬
The sun's still high in the sky.
‫لا تزال الشمس مشرقة.‬
You're better off waiting until dark before crossing the border.
‫يُستحسن أن ننتظر إلى أن يحلّ الظلام‬ ‫قبل أن نعبر الحدود.‬
Picnics sure are fun.
‫النزهات ممتعة مما لا شك فيه.‬
This kind of thing is nice every now and then, isn't it, Dr. Tenma?
‫من الرائع ممارسة أنشطة كهذه‬ ‫من حين لآخر، أليس كذلك يا د. "تينما"؟‬
We've got magnificent scenery and marvelous food.
‫نحن نحظى بمنظر طبيعي خلّاب وطعام شهي.‬
It's times like this when we can feel the joy of being alive.
‫في مثل تلك الأوقات نشعر ببهجة الحياة.‬
I respect doctors like yourself.
‫أحترم من هم مثلك من الأطباء.‬
When a journalist like me writes a good article,
‫عندما يكتب صحفي مثلي مقالًا جيدًا،‬
I can sometimes help people experience the joy of life.
‫يسعني أحيانًا أن أساعد الناس‬ ‫على الشعور ببهجة الحياة.‬
But you can give people the gift of life itself.
‫لكنك تمنح الناس هبة الحياة ذاتها.‬
I have…
‫أنا…‬
I have shot a man.
‫أطلقت النار على رجل.‬
Last month in Munich, I shot a man for the first time.
‫في الشهر الماضي في "ميونخ"،‬ ‫أطلقت النار على رجل لأول مرة.‬
He's probably dead too.
‫على الأرجح أنه مات أيضًا.‬
Before that, my hands would tremble and I couldn't aim straight.
‫قبل أن أُقدم على ذلك،‬ ‫كانت يداي ترتجفان وعجزت عن التصويب.‬
But after shooting a man once, my hands stopped trembling.
‫لكن بعد أن أطلقت النار على الرجل لمرة،‬ ‫توقفت يداي عن الارتجاف.‬
And now,
‫والآن،‬
I am going to have to shoot another man.
‫سأضطر إلى إطلاق النار على رجل آخر.‬
I am… no longer a doctor.
‫لم أعد طبيبًا.‬
Every time I come to the Elbe, I think about
‫في كل مرة آتي فيها إلى "إلبه"،‬
how I would have liked to have brought my son to fish here.
‫يخطر في بالي مدى ما قد أشعر به من فرحة‬ ‫لو كنت أحضرت ابني ليصطاد هنا.‬
Do you mean your dead son?
‫هل تقصد ابنك الميت؟‬
You can catch trout this big.
‫يمكنك اصطياد سمك سلمون مرقط بهذا الحجم.‬
He died without even knowing the joy of fishing.
‫مات دون أن يتعرّف حتى على متعة الصيد.‬
If there had been a doctor like yourself nearby then,
‫لو كان ثمة طبيب مثلك في الجوار آنذاك،‬
I'm sure he could have been saved.
‫لكان أُنقذ بالتأكيد.‬
I mean it. You really can catch trout this big.
‫أعني ذلك حقًا. يمكنك اصطياد‬ ‫سمك سلمون مرقط بهذا الحجم.‬
Cross those mountains and you'll be in the Czech Republic.
‫اعبر تلك الجبال‬ ‫وستصل إلى جمهورية "التشيك".‬
When you get to the forest road beyond it, you can probably hitchhike a ride.
‫عندما تصل إلى طريق الغابة من بعد الجبال،‬ ‫قد تتمكن من أن تجد أحدًا يوصلك.‬
I'll go back to the station from here.
‫سأعود إلى المحطة من هنا.‬
Thank you. You've been an immense help, Mr. Grimmer.
‫شكرًا لك. لقد ساعدتني كثيرًا يا سيد "غريمر".‬
I wish you luck,
‫أتمنى لك حظًا موفقًا،‬
Dr. Tenma.
‫يا دكتور "تينما".‬
Let's have a picnic again the next time we meet.
‫لنخرج في نزهة أخرى‬ ‫في المرة القادمة التي نلتقي فيها.‬
Dr. Tenma.
‫دكتور "تينما".‬
Everyone is burdened with their sins.
‫الجميع مثقلون بخطاياهم،‬
They'll never go away.
‫فهي لا تزول أبدًا.‬
Even so, we still carry on with what we must do.
‫ومع ذلك نستمر‬ ‫في تأدية ما يتوجب علينا تأديته.‬
PRAGUE (CZECH REPUBLIC)
‫"(براغ)، جمهورية (التشيك)"‬
Magnificent.
‫كم هذا مذهل.‬
This really is beautiful.
‫ما أجمله من مكان.‬
I've never been here before,
‫لم آت إلى هنا من قبل،‬
but Prague at night looks like a fairytale land.
‫إن "براغ" أشبه ببلدان القصص الخيالية.‬
Excuse me. May I sit here?
‫عذرًا. أيمكنني الجلوس هنا؟‬
Yeah.
‫نعم.‬
I've really fallen in love with this city.
‫لقد أحببت هذه المدينة جدًا.‬
You're Mr. Petrov, aren't you?
‫أنت السيد "بتروف"، أليس كذلك؟‬
You bought Russian citizenship and now live here in Prague.
‫اشتريت الجنسية الروسية‬ ‫وتعيش هنا في "براغ" الآن.‬
There's something I'd like to ask you.
‫ثمة أمر أود أن أسألك عنه.‬
Would you be willing to answer some questions, Mr. Petrov?
‫هل أنت مستعد للإجابة‬ ‫على بعض الأسئلة يا سيد "بتروف"؟‬
Oh, but isn't your real name Reinhart Biermann?
‫لكن أليس اسمك الحقيقي‬ ‫هو "راينهارت بيرمان"؟‬
There was a special orphanage in East Berlin, wasn't there?
‫كان في "ألمانيا الشرقية" ميتمًا مميزًا،‬ ‫أليس كذلك؟‬
The place was like a laboratory for experimenting
‫كان أشبه بمختبر لإجراء تجارب‬
with chemically induced brainwashing children.
‫لغسل الدماغ المستحث كيميائيًا على الأطفال.‬
It was called Kinderheim 511.
‫كان اسمه "كيندرهايم 511".‬
You were the director there.
‫كنت أنت مديره.‬
Since you were the director, you must know everything about it.
‫بما أنك كنت المدير،‬ ‫فلا بد أنك تعرف عنه كلّ شيء.‬
What were you trying to do there in that place in former East Berlin?
‫ما الذي كنتم تحاولون فعله في ذلك المكان‬ ‫في "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا؟‬
There at Kinderheim 511.
‫في "كيندرهايم 511".‬